# **Joshua Joseph Pickering**

Location: United Kingdom, England, Sheffield Mobile: +447510182764

Email: pickeringjoshua1999@gmail.com Social Links: https://linktr.ee/Encodic

## **Technical Skills**

Languages: Python, C++, C#, Unreal Engine Blueprints

Game Engines: Unreal Engine, Unity, Godot

Developer Tools: Git, Perforce, VS Code, Visual Studio, JetBrains Rider, Figma

#### **About me**

I'm a developer with a history in games and software spanning over multiple years.

I studied Art and Design at college focusing on Game Design and Development, since then heavily self taught gaining experience on personal and professional projects. During college I had work experience as a Game Tester at <a href="Dumpling Design">Dumpling Design</a> aiding future updates to their mobile game 'Smash Tanks!'.

My first ever big project was the freelance work I've done for <u>Moonmen Games</u> on <u>'Worlds Of The Future'</u> an epic open world sci game. I also had the privilege to write a blog post about that project on <u>GameDev.tv</u>. During that time I was also working my first software development job at <u>Dhp11 LTD</u> working on a 3D Telecommunication planning software to aid clients with an accurate 3D representation of their Telecommunication sites utilizing the power of Unreal Engine.

#### Education

#### The Sheffield College, Hillsborough Campus

(2016 - 2018)

Level 3 Extended Diploma In Art and Design – Merit

### **Experience**

#### Co-founder & Lead Gameplay Programmer, WARBOUND, Remote

(April 2024 - Present) Unreal Engine, Perforce, C++, Unreal Engine Blueprints, Blender, Figma

- Co-founded a Game Development team of 7 working on WARBOUND, a WW2 FPS/RTS Hybrid.
- Designed and implemented core gameplay systems, including weapon mechanics and procedural systems.
- Utilized Unreal Engine 5's **Gameplay Ability System and Game Features** to create scalable mechanics.
- Architected a multiplayer-ready codebase, ensuring future expandability.
- Engaged with the community through open development—showcasing progress, discussing technical insights, and gathering feedback.

## Freelance, Moonmen Games, Worlds Of The Future, Remote

(September 2018 - Present) Unreal Engine, Unreal Engine Blueprints, Blender

- Contributed to Worlds of the Future, transitioning from a fan to an integral team member.
- Developed custom pathfinding solutions, procedural structure generation, and aim assist tools.
- Provided QA testing and workflow optimizations, improving development efficiency.
- Created 3D assets and gameplay features, supporting both design and programming needs.

## Developer, Dhp11 ltd, Dronfield

(Full Time, November 2018 - October 2020)

Unreal Engine, Unreal Engine Blueprints, Git, C++, Blender, Python

- Led and aided development on **multiple Unreal Engine projects**, providing technical solutions and maintaining client NDAs.
- Developed automation tools and editor scripts in UE to improve team efficiency.
- Implemented asset processing pipelines, allowing seamless integration of new assets into the client's application.
- Acted as lead developer for key projects, coordinating with cross-functional teams.